{\pos(200,250)\zshad10\be10\blur1\bord1\fad(200,0)\fs28\fsp20\t(0,3482,\fs25\fsp15)\fn方正准圆简体\c&H647BEB&\t(0,1523,\c&H89CAFD&)\4c&H1B1085&\t(0,1523,\4c&H2439CB&)\3c&H2439CB&\move(323.919,84.182,323.919,88.546,21,3482)}美国众神
前情提要
我们是「血亡」
We are Blood Death
本曲献给全能的父
and this is dedicated to the All-Father.
复活神灵可不是你想得那么简单
Resurrecting a god isn't as easy as you'd think.
这个行吗
What about this?
萨梅迪给我的符咒
The gris-gris Samedi gave me.
对他有用吗
Would this work on him?
混合了爱情的血液
Blood... infused with love.
两滴
Two drops.
我现在意识到的现实就是
The reality that I am acknowledging
这个地方他妈烂透了
is that this place sucks donkey dick.
崔克斯法官指定我作为威尔斯小姐的监督人
Judge Trakes appointed me Miss Wells' conservator.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, darling.
你妻子的行为能力也许有所下降
Your wife's capacity may be diminished,
但是她的投资产品很稳健
but her portfolio is robust.
转移  误导
Distract. Misdirect.
让他们关注我们说什么是最重要的
Make them give a fuck about what we say is important.
快来找我  影·穆恩
Come find me, Shadow Moon.
国父们信奉一位造物主
The Founders believed in a creator
他赋予了每个人平等和自由
who endowed every individual with equality and freedom.
美国对这一点深信不疑
America was conceived around that truth
而「独立宣言」就是对这位造物主的誓言
and the Declaration was an oath to that creator.
庄严承诺这个新政府
A solemn promise that this new government
会维护其公民的神圣权利
would ensure the divine rights of its citizens.
包括生命  自由  以及追求幸福的权利
Life, liberty, and a shot at happiness.
但这个新政府负债累累
But the new government was overrun with debt.
激烈的辩论弄得大陆会议乌烟瘴气
Furious debate roiled the Continental Congress:
大陆会议是北美十三州
及后来美利坚合众国的立法机构和临时政府
天赋人权对战唯物主义
God-given rights versus materialism.
最终商业大获全胜
Commerce carried the day
这个年轻的国家逐渐成为了史上最富有的公司
and the young country was on its way to becoming the richest corporation in history.
在此过程中
In the process,
美国背叛了其对造物主的誓言
America betrayed its oath to the creator.
鞭子挥舞之下  经济飞速增长
Economic growth was spurred by the whip
财富留在了奴隶主及其投资者手中
and remained in the hands of the slave masters and their investors.
由棉花之王带来的财富遍布全国
The wealth generated by King Cotton was everywhere.
这个国家如今在商业的祭坛上祈祷
The nation now prayed at the altar of commerce.
但神灵并没有抛弃那些被奴役的人民
But the spirit did not abandon those who had been enslaved,
他们带着非洲的神  奥里莎
who brought their African gods, the Orishas,
一起来到了新世界
with them to the New World.
BGM: Wade In The Water by American Gods Cast
♪涉水而来♪
♪ Wade in the water ♪
♪涉水而来  孩子们♪
♪ Wade in the water, children ♪
♪涉水而来♪
♪ Wade in the water ♪
♪神将会带来水患♪
♪ God's gonna trouble the water ♪
♪看见那位着白衣的主人了吗♪
♪ See that host all dressed in white? ♪
♪神将会带来水患♪
♪ God's gonna trouble the water ♪
♪涉水而来♪
♪ Wade in the water ♪
来自故土的奥里莎啊  我呼唤您
I call upon the Orishas, of the land of the ancestors.
告诉大家我们不是一个人
Show the people that I is not me!
我们是个整体
I is we!
♪涉水而来  孩子们♪
♪ Wade in the water, children ♪
♪涉水而来♪
♪ Wade in the water ♪
♪神将会带来水患♪
♪ God's gonna trouble the water ♪
团结就是力量
And we is power.
神将会带来水患
God's gonna trouble the water
你是我的爱女
You are my beloved.
我是欧桑
I am Oshun.
我会保佑你  给你继续前行的勇气
I will uphold you in your courage to carry life forward.
我是叶玛亚  是水
I am Yemoja, the water.
负担过重  难以为继之时
When the burden is too great,
来我怀里休息吧
you rest in my arms.
我是阿耶
I am Aye,
是你们脚下的土
the earth beneath you.
你们在我身上流血  我的心也为你们滴血
You bleed upon me and I bleed upon you.
终有一天
The time will come
我们将会作为一个整体崛起
when we rise together as one.
正义永不休眠
Justice does not sleep.
正义来自神灵的手中
Righteousness comes from the hand of the divine.
奴隶主的权力减少
The power of the master diminishes.
我们中被奴役的人们
Those of us who have been enslaved
是尘埃中升起的一股力量
are the sole force raised from the dust.
愿你们对明日的美好向往成为今日生活的支柱
May the optimism of tomorrow be your foundation for today
我们是一个整体  团结就是力量
and I is we, and we is power,
如果我们各自为营
and we are powerless
将会无权无力  一无所有
if we just become nothing but you and they.
愿你们内心宁静
May peace be in your hearts
愿奥里莎引领你们前行
and may Orishas lead your way.
带着唯一的爱的祝福
With the blessing of the One Love...
我们勇往直前
We shall overcome.
We shall overcome!
我们勇往直前
{\pos(200,270)\zshad10\be10\blur1\bord2\fad(200,0)\fs28\fsp20\t(0,3482,\fs25\fsp15)\fn方正准圆简体\c&H647BEB&\t(0,1523,\c&H89CAFD&)\4c&H1B1085&\t(0,1523,\4c&H2439CB&)\3c&H2439CB&\move(323.919,84.182,323.919,88.546,21,3482)}美国众神
第三季第四集
你把她怎么了
What'd you do to her?
我说  你他妈到底对她做了什么
I said, what the fuck did you do to her?
什么都没做
Nothing.
我来这里是因为那个贱人对我干的事
I am here because of what that bitch did to me!
-我不相信你  -那有部手机
- I don't believe you. - There's a phone--
不  等等  等等  等等
No, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
你他妈什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
我告诉过你了  比奇丝把我搞惨了
I told you: Bilquis fucked me up.
我需要她这个系铃人把铃铛解开
I need her to unfuck whatever it is that she did to me.
不不  等等  住手  住手
No, no, wait, stop. Stop, stop, stop, stop!
住手  快住手
Stop! Just stop it!
我觉得我貌似搞清楚这里发生什么了
I think I might have figured out what went down here.
那你说吧  赶紧
So talk. Fast.
比奇丝在这里勾搭的最后一个人
The last person that Bilquis hooked up with here
是...比尔·桑德斯
was... Bill Sanders.
就是那位比尔·桑德斯
The Bill Sanders.
如果你想撒谎的话
If you are going to lie,
起码得撒得可信些
make it believable.
我说的是真话
I'm telling you.
他来过这里
He was here.
镜头1
前门
亿万富翁慈善家  科技大神
Billionaire philanthropist, tech guru,
镜头4
楼梯
同时也是里维科技计算系统的创始人
and founder of Levitech Computing Systems
偷偷来这里见比奇丝
was meeting Bilquis here on the low.
但妹子有办法把人...弄不见
But homegirl has a way of making people... disappear,
时不时的
from time to time.
他从没离开  所以...
He never left, which is why...
他的手机还在这里
his phone is still here.
这依旧没有解释比奇丝去哪了
Still doesn't explain where Bilquis is.
你问的是发生了什么
You asked me what happened.
我在解释这一点
I am enlightening you.
镜头1
前门
把手机给我
Gimme the phone.
什么
What?
不不不  我和你一起去
No, no, no, no, no, no. I am coming with you.
我可不这么想  快他妈把手机给我
I don't think so. Give me the fucking phone.
我告诉过你了  我需要比奇丝
I told you, I need Bilquis.
你个白痴王八蛋
You fucking dipshit!
无论她对你做了什么  八成是你活该
Whatever she did to you, you probably deserved it.
我自己去找她
I'll find her on my own.
你有17条未读信息  第一条...
You have 17 unheard messages. First message...
爸  希望你收到我的短信了
Hi, Dad. Hope you're getting my messages.
一切都还好吗
Is everything okay?
给我回电  拜托
Call me. Please.
亚历珊德拉·桑德斯
Alexandra Sanders.
比尔·桑德斯的长女
Bill Sanders' eldest daughter.
根据桑德斯联系人信息看  她是哥大的助教
Assistant professor at Columbia according to Sanders' contacts.
她留了十条语音信息
Now, she has left 10 voicemails,
每一条都比上一条更急切担忧
each one more desperate than the last.
如果桑德斯有保镖
If Sanders had a security detail,
他生出来的后代肯定也有
so do the heirs who sprang from his loins.
对
Yeah.
我们从他女儿的保镖下手
We lean on one of his daughter's body men,
就能找到比奇丝
they'll give us Bilquis.
你还真是个神探呢
Gold star for Nancy Drew.
叫你当时处死我  活该
That's for lynching me, peckerwood.
我已经道过歉了
I already apologized for that.
不接受
Apology not accepted.
永远不会
Not now. Not ever.
我不是一个人
I am not alone.
我选择坚信
I choose to believe that.
我必须坚信
I have to believe that.
我不是一个人
I am not alone.
我选择坚信
I choose to believe that.
我必须坚信
I have to believe that.
我不是一个人
I am not alone.
桑德斯是个熟客
Sanders was a regular.
差不多一年了  每周都会去见她一次
Been seeing her once a week for over a year now.
问题是她在为谁工作
The question is, who's she working for?
你的高祖母
Your great-great-grandmother?
对  她当时可算个人物
Oh yeah, she was a personage.
她是路易斯安那州首位黑人女性律师
She was the first black woman lawyer in Louisiana.
这还有不少你不知道的事
There's lots to learn here.
戴蒙  你在跑哪
Hey, Damon. Where you at?
戴蒙
Damon?
再不过来我就要揍你了
Come on over here before I kick your poo butt.
爸爸
Papa!
爸爸  爸爸
Papa! Papa!
欢迎各位
炼狱  新人指南
认清现实
你带没带烟啊
Pst. I don't suppose you've got a smoke on you, do ya?
我倒希望我带了
Oh, I wish.
我可是一天抽三包的人
Three-pack-a-day girl over here.
等我得了喉癌  医生又叫我
When I got throat cancer, my doctor said I had
改变生活习惯
to change my lifestyle.
我就改吸了薄荷脑
So I switched to menthol.
那挺好啊
Hm! Nice.
等我们经历所有磨难之后
Um, so, once we've jumped through all of the hoops,
你知道具体什么时候才能离开这吗
do you know when the fuck we finally get outta here?
这是死亡的谜团之一
One of death's great mysteries.
我要是你  我可不会
I wouldn't spend a whole lotta time
为了搞清这个花那么多时间
trying to figure it out if I were you.
不然你就会变得跟那个蠢蛋一样
Or you'll end up like that sorry son-of-a-bitch.
这个人
This guy?
我是1993年夏天去世的
I died summer of '93.
那会他就这熊样
He was like that then.
从那之后就没变过
Nothing's changed since.
这么奇葩
Yikes.
持有红卡的旅客请注意
Attention. Those with red cards,
请前往指定区域
please make your way to the designated area...
没门
No.
仅限红卡持有者
Red card holders only.
你有没有见过
You haven't by any chance seen a guy in here:
大高个  红头发  咋咋呼呼
super tall, red hair, big mouth,
态度嚣张  像是爱尔兰人的一个人
bad attitude, Irish-ish?
没见过
I don't believe so.
但我对人不大留意
But I'm not much of a people watcher.
如果你见过他  绝对忘不了的
Oh, you would remember this guy if you saw him, trust me.
他就算在人群里也很显眼
He's pretty hard to miss.
所以你就喜欢那种坏男人  是吧
So, you're into the bad boys, are you?
才不是
Oh no, ew.
不是那么一回事
No, that's not what it was like at all.
不是
Oh, no.
以你刚才的描述
You were just talking like...
他听着像特别的人
...maybe he's someone special.
♪ Worlds end ♪
♪ Stars dimmed ♪
♪ Dark falls ♪
♪ But your magic ♪
♪ Still remains ♪
♪ I'm here ♪
♪ You're gone ♪
♪ Hearts break ♪
不行  绝对不行
No, no, no!
♪ Will your magic see me ♪
♪ Can I ♪
♪ Go on ♪
♪ Without you ♪
其实  他是杀我的凶手
Actually, he... is the guy who killed me.
对
Yup.
请注意
Attention.
持有红卡的旅客
Those with red cards, please make your way
现在请前往指定区域
to the designated area at this time.
这个傻逼哈钦森自以为能忽悠我
This Hutchinson pinhead thinks he can get one over on me.
我忘掉的骗术
Ha. I've forgotten more about long cons
都比他知道的多
than he'll ever know.
已经黑进他的企业账户了
Hacked into his business accounts.
保护者个屁
Conservator, my ass.
他就是个吸血鬼
He's a vampire.
专吸老弱病残
Preying on the elderly and infirm.
就别提抹黑厄琉西斯密仪了
Never mind defaming the Eleusinian mysteries.
好
Okay.
恰好在开曼群岛
Hello, Cayman Islands.
找对了
Bingo.
这老哥可谓轻车熟路
Man, this guy's got it all figured out.
离岸账户
Offshore accounts,
把从客户信托那里敛来的财
money being siphoned from the client trusts into...
看不到转移到哪去了  有防火墙
Firewall won't let me see where.
如果你想要那种
If you want proof of the
能掐住他要害的证据
stringing-him-up-by-the-balls variety,
我必须得接触到他的电脑
I'm gonna need access to his computer,
他的硬盘
like the actual hard drive.
蠢货里他算狡猾的了
A crafty pinhead, he is.
好
Fine.
那就进他家里的办公室拿吧
A home office B-and-E it is then.
说不定还能来一出父子戏
Perhaps a father and son two-hander.
好戏开始
Game on.
服务员呢
Now, where's that waitress?
我他妈要饿死了
I am fucking starving!
好
All right.
女儿的司机在那
There's the daughter's driver.
后面还有一辆车
And the follow car.
看见没
See?
带我来是不是有好处
Aren't you glad you brought me along?
没事  兄弟
It's alright, buddy.
绕个路吧
Little detour.
吉尔伯特  这事算是了结了
Well, Gilbert, the excitement appears to be concluded
这倒霉蛋的尸骨
and this poor man's remains
也要火化了
are about to be given to the furnace,
把这好好清理干净吧
so let's clean it up real good in here.
可怜的家伙
Poor fella.
任何人都不该这样离世
That is no way for a soul to be leaving this world.
再怎么也是神的子民
Someone oughta be holding a high thought
下手也该讲个轻重
for that child of God.
好好清理吧
Knock yourself out, Gilbert.
真行
Great. Great!
这简直就一块砖
A brick!
还没信号
And no bars.
你要找的东西肯定不在那里面
Whatever you're looking for, you won't find it in that.
我们就用那种低端非智能手机
We like our phones empty and dumb.
就像你俩一样蠢
Like you two idiots.
她在哪
Where is she?
一次性手机
Burner phones.
用完就能扔
Disposable.
无法追踪
Untraceable.
我知道你不喜欢无线通讯
I know wireless isn't your jam,
但这样不会让我们被监测到
but... it'll keep us under the radar.
我们将彻底销声匿迹  连国安局的那帮混蛋
We'll be so off the grid not even the assholes at the NSA
都无法追踪到我们
will be able to track us,
他们能追踪所有人
and they track everybody, just 'cause.
我觉得电话号码
I don't think phone numbers
没有那么多位
actually have that many digits.
准确来说是21位
21, to be exact.
在北欧神话体系下三是个很重要的数字
Three is a very important number in Norse mythology,
象征着王室
signifying royalty.
七也同等重要  象征着完整
Seven is of equal stature, representing completeness.
你算算吧
Do the math.
三乘以七是
Three times seven is...
知道了
Got it.
你好
Hello?
是找你的
It's for you.
那是条保密线路
That's a secure line.
很显然并不是  蠢货
Well, apparently not, dickhead.
现在把嘴闭上
Now, shut the fuck up.
你好
Hello?
影子
Shadow?
是我
Yeah.
你爸想和你聊聊
Your father would like a word.
你好  我的孩子
Hello, my boy.
我现在挺忙的
Okay, I am kind of in the middle of something.
我在马萨诸塞州有活给你干
I need you for a job up here in Massachusetts.
开车差不多三小时就到
Should take about three hours to drive up?
不可能的
Not happening.
好吧
Okay...
等我找到比奇丝后再聊
we'll talk after I find Bilquis.
他不来吗
No luck?
看来我们得找别的方法
Looks like we'll have to find
来营救我的新娘了
another way to rescue my bride.
我们之间没有必要变得这么对立
There's no reason for this to turn adversarial.
把关押她的地点给我们
So, just give us the location of where she's being held,
你就能回去干自己的活了
you get to go about your business.
你们是谁
Who are you guys?
条件是这样的  蠢货
Okay, here is the deal, shithead.
你要把我们想知道的告诉我们
You are going to tell us what we need to know,
不然我们会用煤油
or we are going to peel your fucking skin off
将你的皮肤剥下来  懂了吗
with fucking kerosene. You dig?
煤油
Kerosene?
认真的吗
Seriously?
拜托你别这么紧绷  稍微松松劲儿
I'm gonna need you to dial it back to about a two.
我来吧
I'll handle this.
你真的不知道你在和谁打交道
You really have no idea who you're dealing with.
你听说过外星人计划吗  没有吗
You ever hear of the alien agenda? No?
这远远超出你的水平
'Cause you are so far out of your league,
你根本不知道你面对的是什么情况
you don't even know what game you're playing.
你得快点开口
You need to start talkin'
不然你就会看到一些让你终身难忘的东西
or you're gonna start to see some shit that you really can't unsee.
从他脑袋里喷出来的东西是什么
What's that stuff spraying out of his head?
你知道吗
You know what?
给他点厉害尝尝
Give him a taste.
做过肠镜吗  马克
Ever been probed, Mark?
被短灰人  高白人抓起来
You know, grabbed up by the Greys, Tall Whites,
你什么都不会记得
you never remember a thing, but...
但是他那种外星人
...his kind.
不管你多么想忘记
Yeah, that shit you never forget...
那种事你是无法忘记的
...no matter how hard you try.
我们先从繁殖系统开始
We'll be starting with the reproductive system.
不不不  等等等等
No, no, no! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
她在霍博肯
She's in Hoboken!
她被关在
She's being held, um...
木材供应厂
...in a building behind the, uh,
后面的那栋楼里
behind the lumber supply!
我们走吧
Let's go.
「碎片大厦」的进度已经远远落后于初定内容了
We're behind schedule on the initial components for SHARD.
-为什么  -这不是我们的错
- Why? - It's not our fault.
我们应经准备好对基线算法进行内部测试了
We're ready to alpha test baseline algorithms.
这就是你遮羞的方式吗
Is that the sound of you covering your anus?
我们的软件供应商里维那边有个问题
There's a problem with our software suppliers, Levitech.
什么样的问题
What kind of problem?
董事会里一片混乱
Total chaos in the boardroom.
他们在尽一切努力不让事情曝光
They're doing their best to keep it under wraps,
但我们做了些研究发现威廉·桑德斯失踪了
but we did some digging and William Sanders is MIA.
投资者得到了风声  道琼斯指数一路下跌
Investors catch wind, the Dow craters.
地球上最厉害的人之一
How exactly does one of the most
是怎么失踪的
powerful men on the planet go missing?
很显然是从一个曼哈顿的应召女郎家里失踪的
In a Manhattan call-girl's apartment, apparently.
至于是怎么失踪的  我不太想推测
As to how, I wouldn't want to speculate.
-至于偶发事件  -给我滚出去
- As far as contingency-- - Get the fuck out.
好的
Okay.
展示新泽西州  霍博肯的
Show me Levitech Server Farm Number 37.
里维第37号服务器集群
Hoboken, New Jersey.
这他妈的
Oh, for fuck's sake.
镜头5
我早该料到的
I should've known.
他妈的疯婊子
Crazy fucking bitch.
有人很帅
Somebody's handsome.
安息吧
Peaceful rest.
亲爱的孩子
Dear child...
你可以哼得小声点么
could you please hum more quietly?
你知道这首歌是什么吗  旋律是
Do you, do you know what song this is? It's like...
有人知道吗  有人知道这首是什么歌吗
Anybody? Does anybody know what this song is?
求求你们了  旋律是
Please? It's like:
请告诉我这是什么歌
Somebody please tell me what this fucking song is.
这是施维格的「巴尔德的镇魂歌」
It's Schwieger's Requiem of Balder.
-你在这干什么  -喝咖啡
- What are you doing here? - Coffee.
后面都没人能煮新的一壶
No one in the back ever makes a fresh pot.
你能告诉我这首歌是什么吗
Can you please tell me what this song is
我小时候看的某部电影
that was playing in the background all the time
它背景音乐一直是这首
when I was a kid in the movie thing?
这一定代表了什么
It must mean something.
-像是什么  -我也不知道
- Like what? - I don't know.
-你是那个炼狱人  -向导
- You're the Purgatory guy. - Guide.
-我是炼狱向导  -好的
- I'm the Purgatory guide. - Okay, good.
你要不是个万事通的话  也许
If you weren't such a know-it-all, and maybe
你应该多待一会
you'd hung around a little while longer,
也许能了解更多
you might've found out more.
-例如什么  -你拥有强大的命运
- Like what? - You have a powerful destiny.
那他妈是什么意思
Whatever the fuck that means.
那是说你会吸引强大的敌人
It means you attract powerful enemies.
是啊  我被一个战神杀死了
Well, yeah. I mean, I was killed by a war god.
那个敌人是挺强大的
It's a pretty fucking powerful enemy.
-好吧  -好吧
- Okay. - Okay, well,
那和这首歌有什么关系
what does it have to do with the song?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
这是像
Well, is it like, uh,
他的主题曲什么的吗
his theme song or something?
像是首战神斗曲吗
Like a war god fight song?
还有人看见了吗
Did anybody else see that?
嗨
Hi.
刚刚管子上
There was a kink in the...
打了个结  然后
...hose. And then...
你是从哪  你是从哪里来的
Where did you... Where did you come from?
炼狱
Um, Purgatory?
-你一定冷了  -是啊
- You must be cold. - Yeah.
是啊
Yeah.
操
Shit.
我活过来了
I'm alive.
是的女士  我想你是活过来了
Yes, ma'am. I believe you are.
-这是我的血吗  -不是
- Is this mine? - No.
也有可能
Or maybe.
我不太清楚
I can't really tell.
我想可能是之前的尸体上的
I... think it's from the body that was here.
高个子  红头发吗
Oh. Tall guy? Red hair?
-是的  -那是斯维尼
- Yeah. - Oh, that's Sweeney.
你知道他去哪里了吗
Um, do you happen to know where he went?
他被运走了  就不久前
Took him away. Little while ago.
至少是剩下的部分
What was left of him anyway.
他们要火化遗体
They're cremating the remains.
好吧  那么他确实死了
Okay, so he's dead.
是真的死了  完全死掉了
Like, actually dead. Completely dead.
而这都是我的错
And it's my fault.
不不不
No, no, no.
我没杀他  就只是...
I didn't kill him. Heh. Just, um...
没法救活他
Just couldn't bring him back to life,
本来我是可以做到的
which I should've been able to do.
但我没有
But I didn't.
说来话长了
It's a long story.
是我就不会这么责怪自己
Well, I wouldn't be too hard on yourself.
就像那本书中说的 世间万物有生
Like the book says, there's a time to be born
就有死
and there's a time to die.
是  但是不能因为有人在书里这么写了
Right. But just because somebody wrote it in a book
-就把它当做真理  -是没错
- doesn't mean it's true. - Fair enough.
我想我只是那种
I guess I'm just someone
相信不管他身处何方
who's inclined to believe that wherever he is,
那都是他的命运所在
that's where he's supposed to be.
BGM: Don't Stand Still by Harmony on Mars
♪ Do you think you're above everyone ♪
♪ you know yourself well ♪
看着点  你个蠢货
Watch it, you fucking moron.
-说我是个蠢货  -没错  你就是
- I'm a fucking moron? - Fuck yeah, you are.
这是种不打算让居民受惊吓的
This is a home invasion with no specific intention
家园入侵
of terrorizing the inhabitants,
虽然我不介意让那些无生气的
although I wouldn't mind if the bloodless milksop
胆小鬼丈夫干点脏活
of a husband gets dirtied up a little, huh?
他需要看到他的世界崩溃
He just needs to see his world crumble
而我只需要他的电脑
and I just... need his computer.
-你有什么毛病  -有这个
- What the fuck is wrong with you? - This.
你听着呢吗
You listening?
有
Yeah.
没问题  24小时内交给你
Yeah. You got it. You'll have it in 24 hours.
-很好  -但是兄弟  我需要你帮个忙
- Good. - But brother, I need a favor.
说吧
Well, say it.
那个狗屎约翰每次一出现
Every time that shit-stain Johan comes in here,
就会惹出麻烦
he causes a problem.
我想让那蠢货
I want that fucking ape
从这里滚出去  不然就让他见血
out of here or he bleeds.
我来处理
I'll handle it.
他什么来头
So, what's his story?
传奇
Legend.
他在1978年骑着一辆哈雷61扁头摩托
He rode a '61 Flathead up Whiteface Mountain
顶着暴风雪上怀特费斯山
in the blizzard of '78.
每小时160公里的风速  一米厚的冰雪
100-mile-an-hour winds, sheet ice three feet thick.
来啊  上啊  上啊
Come on, bring it! Bring it! Bring it!
后来无人可以企及
No one else since has even come close.
在面试乐队新成员吗  约翰
Auditioning new bandmates, Johan?
他们说那是不可能做到的事
They say it ain't possible.
在星期三身上  规则如同虚无
With Wednesday, rules just don't apply.
先生们  别这样
Gentlemen! Come on, come on!
这一切都是一场大误会  对不对  约翰
This is all a... a big misunderstanding, isn't it, Johan?
你不想伤到任何人  对吧
You didn't mean any harm, did you?
不  没有  他不是有意的
No. No, he means no harm.
无论如何  据我所知
Anyway, as far as I know,
不是有老话说  真正的派对
isn't it true that the party doesn't start
在没见点血之前就不算开始  是吧
unless a little blood has been spilled, huh?
这样好多了  来吧
That's better. Come on.
来吧  约翰
Come on, Johan!
老板  给所有人来一杯
Innkeeper, drinks all around, huh?
别把帮手干掉了好吗  孩子
Try not to kill the help, my boy. Huh?
他们的吹捧在支撑我们
Their adulation sustains us.
我有时候会忘记规则  好吗
I sometimes forget the rules, okay?
我明白
I understand.
你依然在为乐队成员的去世悲伤
You're still grieving your bandmates.
他们是我的兄弟  我的家人
They were my... brothers, my family.
我会找出是谁杀了他们
And I will find whoever fucking killed them,
我要活剥了他们的皮
and I will skin them alive.
是你杀了他们吗
Did you kill them?
没有  你为什么这么问我  我没有
No, I... Why would you ask me that? No!
我温和  可爱
Oh, my gentle, sweet,
嗜血的火熊
blood-drinking fire-bear.
事实是这样的
The facts are these:
你经常会发狂
you frequently do go ape-shit,
在那种境界下
and in such states,
你不会记得自己做了什么错事
do not remember what fell deeds you do.
那可能是场意外
It could've been an accident.
可能是任何人杀了那个乐队
Anyone could kill that band.
很多人都想过
Many want to.
但是要记住
But, remember, huh?
我们需要
We need...
你的音乐能够召集的所有门徒
all the disciples that your music can gather.
所以你需要组成一个新的乐队
So, you must form a new band.
我没有杀他们
I did not kill them!
听我说
Listen to me.
给我回家去
Go the fuck home.
好好睡一觉
Sleep it off.
然后  照我说的去做
And then, do what I fucking tell you.
好吗
Okay?
是的  全能的父
Yes, All-Father.
我祈求我的神
I cry to my god,
但是他不在王座之上
but his throne is empty!
敬我们至高无上的神
To the god in whose name we stand tall!
奥丁万岁
Hail Odin!
熟悉的面孔
Familiar faces.
我与
I have a close
里维有着紧密的战略合作
strategic partnership with Levitech,
我同意
and I agreed
你可以从桑德斯先生那里
that you could accept worship
获取崇拜
from Mr. Sanders
但前提是你不能去
with the provision that you did not
献祭他
facilitate his sacrifice.
我与我门徒之间的事情
What transpires between my worshippers and I
与你无关
is none of your concern.
那让我们把这一页翻过去吧
Let's... turn a page on the past, then.
你和我
You and me.
新神  与旧神
New God... to old Goddess.
如果你全心全意侍奉新神
If you fully commit to the new gods,
你作为典型  将能够说服
your example will persuade
旧联盟中的很多人
many in the old alliance
去反对逼近我们的战争
to reject this war looming over us all!
星期三不可能独自迎战
Wednesday can't go into battle by himself.
你总是这套话
It's always the same speech with you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们的技术将会  重新定义
Our technology will... revolutionize
人与神之间的关系
man's relationship with the divine.
新神与旧神将会与门徒的思想
New gods and old gods will have a direct interface
有着直接的交流
with the minds of our worshippers.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
你离不开这里
You're not getting out of here.
除非比尔·桑德斯奇迹般的出现
Unless Bill Sanders miraculously appears
解决这场误会
and clears up this misunderstanding.
我们都知道这是不可能的
We both know that is not going to happen.
我想要救你的命
I am trying to save your life.
我不是一个人
I'm not alone.
我有爱
I... I have love.
你这是走到尽头了
Haven't you come to the end?
我有爱  我有爱
I have love. I have love.
我希望不会太痛苦
I hope it's not too painful.
下一步吗
Next steps?
如果她依然拒绝说出桑德斯的下落
If she still refuses to give up Sanders' whereabouts,
我们不能冒险让她成为别人的情报线人
we can't risk her becoming an intelligence asset to someone else.
扁鼠和疣猪关店了
Pressed Rat and Warthog have closed down their shop.
他们虽然不愿意  但也只能这样了
They didn't want to, 'twas all they had got.
卖「无调苹果」
Selling atonal apples,
「放大热量」
amplified heat,
还有扁鼠杂七杂八的唱片
and Pressed Rat's collection of dog legs and feet.
别挡路  混蛋
Get out of the way, asshole!
恶心的脏老头
Disgusting dirty old man!
那话不错  混蛋
Nice cock, asshole!
老爹来电话了
Daddy's calling.
自助
-喂  -影子  谢天谢地
- Hello? - Oh, Shadow, thank God.
等等  你没事吧
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Y-you all right?
我没事  但是有个叫约翰的疯子
I'm fine, but some whack-job berserker named Johan
把飙车族酒吧给炸了  当时你爸就在里面
blew up the biker bar while your dad was inside.
-他...  -很遗憾  他们走了...
- Is he... - Sadly, they left...
-他没事  -...没跟任何人告别
- He's fine. - ...telling no one good-bye.
他有事  他身体没什么问题
He's not fine. He's okay physically,
但是脑子糊涂了
but his head is a mess.
疣猪一条条纹领带
...Warthog a striped tie.
我们正在送他去医院
We're checking him into a hospital now.
一家特诊医院  精神病院
It's like a... a special hospital. A nuthouse.
这可真是时候  是吧
It's about fucking time, though, really, right?
很严重
This is serious!
好吧  好吧
All right, all right, all right...
-你没事吧  -还行  不过...
- Are you okay? - More or less, but...
好  可是  听我说
Okay, well, listen, listen. I, um...
我这边有点情况  但是
I-I've got a situation on my hands here, but...
我知道你跟你爸之间有些不愉快
I know you and your dad have beef,
但我从没见过他这个样子
but I've never seen him like this.
你得来一趟
You need to come.
求你了
Please.
油箱满了
Tank's full.
他现在安全了  对吧
Look, um, he's safe right now, yeah?
算是吧  只要给他穿上约束衣之类的
Yeah, I guess, once they get him into a straitjacket or something.
尽你全力  确保他的安全
Do whatever you can. Make sure he's safe.
-我们明天再聊  -我真的认为你应该...
- We'll talk tomorrow. - I really think you should...
自助
普通柴油
我得挂了  我会尽快联系你  拜拜
I-I gotta go. Okay? Uh, we'll talk as soon as I can. Bye.
有个猴子在我裤子里拉屎了
A monkey shat in my pants.
都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be okay.
你精致
You are exquisite.
如珠宝
A jewel.
巧克力般的肌肤
Your chocolate skin.
-眼神迷离  -对
- Your hypnotic gaze. - Yes.
继续说
Tell me more.
神秘
Mysterious.
洋气
Exotic.
你诱惑我  吞噬我
You tempt me, you devour me.
你邪恶的美
You wicked beauty.
我必须要你  进入你
I have to have you, to be inside you.
-进入你  -崇拜我
- Be inside you. - Worship me!
你为我而生  我的女神
You were made for me, my goddess.
你为我而生
You were made for me.
闭嘴
Be silent!
我不是你口中的那样
I am not what you say.
我不是为你而生  我生在希瓦之前
I was not made for you. I was before Shiva,
在阿佛洛狄特之前  在文字之前
I was before Aphrodite, before the word.
我不是一个人
I am not alone!
我知道  也被世人知晓
I knew and was known.
我是...
I was...
我的名字...
My name was...
你是谁
Who are you?
我了解你  就像你了解我一样
I know you as you know me.
我们是一个整体
I... is we.
欧桑
Oshun.
看看你自己
Look at yourself.
看你甜美真实的自己
See your sweet, true self.
看清你是谁的真相
See the truth in who you are.
看清你一直以来的自己
And who you have always been.
我不是一个人
I am not alone.
你是我的爱女
You are my beloved.
我会保佑你
I will uphold you in your courage
给你继续前行的勇气
as you carry life forward.
他们所说的  不是真正的你
You are not who they say you are.
你想成为谁  就成为谁
You are whoever you want to be.
我一直都是她
I am she who has always been.
我们好像把她弄崩溃了
I think we broke her.
糟糕
Oops.
天啊
Oh, my God.
真好吃  真神奇
Tasting. What a concept.
其实  这样是不符合规定的
You know, this ain't exactly according to regulations.
这就是他吗
So, this is him?
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
他的全部就这样装在里面了
All of him somehow fits in here.
♪ I'm here ♪
♪ You're gone ♪
♪ Hearts break ♪
希望你不会觉得我太冒昧  不过
You know, I hope you don't find me too forward, but, um,
遇见你这样的人让人有了信念
meeting someone like you kinda gives a man faith.
什么样的信念  我还说不好
In what, I... can't exactly say.
我也说不好
Yeah, me neither.
我认为  这就是让我们相信
You know, I think it comes down to just
我们看不到的事情
believing in somethin' we can't see
因为我们知道它的存在
'cause we know it's there.
这就是我们继续前进的动力
That's what keeps us going.
也许吧
Maybe so.
好了  谢谢你
Well, thank you.
我该走了
I'm-I'm gonna, I'm gonna get going.
我多嘴问一下  你要去哪
Where to, if you don't mind me asking?
我也没想好  不过
I'm not exactly sure yet but, um...
我要去找个人问一首歌
I've gotta go see a man about a song.
-祝你好运  -你也是
- Well, good luck. - You too.
女士
Señorita.
他说我们要在这拐弯了
He say this is where we turn.
你要继续往北走  对吧
You go more norte, si?
是的
Uh, si.
应该是往北
Norte, I think.
好的
Okay.
小姐  路上小心
Señorita, tengo cuidado.
你们也是   谢谢
You too. Thanks.
卡车驿站
你不会是往北走吧
You're not going north by any chance, are you?
就是往北
Sure as hell am.
-你要去哪  -伊利诺伊州开罗
- Where you headed? - Cairo, Illinois?
上来吧
Hop in.
BGM: Feeling Good (Electric) by Willow Robinson
♪ Birds flying high ♪
♪ You know how I feel ♪
♪ Sun in the sky ♪
♪ Breeze driftin' on by ♪
♪ You know how I feel ♪
♪ It's a new dawn It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life ♪
♪ And I'm feeling good ♪
♪ Fish in the sea ♪
♪ Know how I feel ♪
♪ River running free ♪
♪ You know how I feel ♪
♪ Blossom on a tree ♪
♪ It's a new dawn It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life ♪
♪ And I'm feeling good ♪